raindance.org 2019-05-05

# Raindance Privacy Policy - Raindance

Raindance is committed to keeping your personal information (data) safe and meeting our responsibilities under privacy law. Privacy law in the UK has recently changed under the General Data Protection Regulation, which has come into force on the 25th May 2018, and which our policy reflects. You can find general information about data protection law on the ICO’s website: <https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/>

This policy is intended to let you know how we use the data we hold about you, and your rights in regard to this. It does not provide exhaustive detail, but we are happy to provide more information or explanation on request – please email [info@raindance.co.uk](mailto:info@raindance.co.uk).

Our privacy policy may be reviewed from time to time and we will share any updates on this website. We may also get in touch directly to let you know about significant changes. This privacy policy was last updated on 25th May 2018.

#### Who we are

We are Raindance Film Partnership LLP at 10A Craven Street, London WC2N 5PE. Our phone number is 0207 930 3412.

### Who you are

You are an individual who has interacted with Raindance in one or more of these ways (please note, this list is not necessarily exhaustive):  
• Used the Raindance website (which is currently at www.raindance.org)  
• Asked to join our mailing list or our Network  
• Completed an online or paper feedback form or survey  
• Contacted us via email or interacted with us on social media  
• Donated money to Raindance online (through a third party like Kickstarter, PayPal, MyDonate or JustGiving), or by bank transfer, cheque, cash or services in kind  
• Booked to attend a Raindance screening, performance, or event  
• Participated in a Raindance project (or are the parent or guardian of a child under the age of 18 who has participated in a Coney project)  
• Been nominated by someone you know to receive a Raindance award  
• Been selected by Raindance to receive a surprise message, adventure or gift, using publicly available contact details  
• Texted a Raindance mobile phone  
• Told another company that they can pass information about you to Raindance This privacy policy does not cover personal data we hold about you as an employee, trustee, supplier, freelancer or sole trader who we work with or have discussed working with. What data we may hold about you Data we hold about you may include:  
• Photographs and videos taken during a Raindance class, screening, project or event  
• Information you gave us in an online or paper form (such as feedback, contact details, and information like your age, ethnicity and gender)  
• Details of Raindance performances and events you have attended, and purchases or donations you have made. These may include information available through services we use to process bookings, donations and payments, currently wooCommerce, Eventbrite, PayPal, Kickstarter and Indiegogo.  
• Communications with us (such as emails and notes of phone calls) and any information you send us via email (such as your CV)  
• Information you gave to during the course of a project or event, in order for us to create an interactive experience (such as a questionnaire to get to know you better in advance of attending). We will only use this data in order to deliver the experience, and will delete it as soon as it is no longer needed.  
• Your publicly available social media activity and interactions with Raindance (such as your Twitter handle, posts about us, and your location)  
• Publicly available information we have discovered about you through research, in the course of delivering a Raindance event or project you signed up for, or for which a friend referred you. Using the principle of loveliness, we will make sure information collected is appropriate, and will use it only as long as required to deliver your adventure.

#### How we use data about you

• We collect and hold data about you so we can do things like:  
• Create and deliver experiences, adventures, and performances. Our work is interactive, so we often need to know a bit about you to make it possible. The way we use your data varies between projects, but always follows Raindance’s principles of adventure, curiosity and loveliness.  
• Learn from your experience and feedback, to develop our work and tailor it to our audiences and participants  
• Keep track of who has come to which Raindance screenings, classes and events  
• Personalise the communications you receive from us  
• Manage our organisation effectively at an administrative level  
• Record who has given money or services to us, so we can keep you informed about how this has impacted our work, and claim GiftAid where possible  
• Keep in touch with you as someone who may want to collaborate with us  
• Send you information about Raindance, our events and ways to support us.

**Depending on what you have asked to hear about, this may include:**

• Sending you messages about Raindance’s work, events and performances, ways to support us, and occasional details about work by our friends  
• Updating you on projects you have previously been involved in o  
• Sending you event invitations, news and opportunities specifically relating to Raindance’s nettwork  
• Share with other people and organisations the feedback you have given us, in order to promote Raindance’s work and report on our impact.

#### Use of anonymous data

We share statistics about our audiences and participants with third parties (such as Arts Council England, BFI and venue partners) to report on our work, which may include data you gave us in a form. This kind of information will always be anonymised.

We use a third-party provider, MailChimp, to deliver our newsletters. Through this, we gather anonymous statistics about email opening and clicks.

We use Google Analytics to collect basic log information and details of what visitors do on our website, as well as information provided by your computer, like your browser type. This data is anonymised and we will never attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

#### Cookies

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

By visiting our website, you consent to the use of cookies – files placed on your computer by a website to collect standard internet log data and learn about the behaviour of visitors. For more information about cookies, including how to turn them off, visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

#### Children/young people

Raindance is committed to the welfare needs of all children, young people and vulnerable adults who work with Coney, whether they are participating in Raindance workshops or are performers or makers on Raindance projects. We aim to create intimate, respectful and trusting relationships with everyone involved.

**Raindance is committed to a creative process which:**

• Places the welfare of children, young people and vulnerable adults first;  
• Respects the rights, wishes and feelings of young people, vulnerable adults and all with whom we are working  
• Promotes the welfare of all people we work with and their protection within a relationship of trust;  
• Ensures best health and safety practice. In our participation projects, we may collect data about the people taking part, including children & young people. We will seek consent from a parent or guardian before collecting data about children.

In order to deliver projects and keep participants safe, we may need information like medical details, school information, access requirements and notes and feedback on participants’ work with Raindance. This may be passed to emergency services if necessary. For people under 16 years old, Coney will use a nominated adult as the first point of communication, switching to the child on consent from that nominated adult or where needed to fulfil a contract.

#### How we keep your data safe, and who sees it

To protect your privacy, we make sure your data is kept securely and access is restricted to appropriately trained staff who need to use it for the processes outlined in this policy. We will keep and process your data only for long enough to fulfil the purpose we collected it for. After that point, we will dispose of in a secure manner.

We will never sell your data, but it may be processed by limited third parties in the course of achieving the purposes listed above. Third parties that may process your data for us include payment platforms, venues who need the names of bookers, ticket sites, and companies who store our data.

Some of our suppliers run their operations outside the European Economic Area (EEA). This means they may not be subject to same data protection laws as companies based in the UK, but we will take steps to make sure they provide a level of protection which meets the requirements of UK data protection law.  
We may share information about you with law enforcement agencies and other organisations or individuals if we are required to by law.

Contacting us, access to your data, and your right of correction or erasure  
We want to make sure that the data we hold about you is accurate and up to date, and you can ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate. You also have the right to ask us to ‘forget’ you, by erasing the data we hold about you as far as reasonably possible. If you would like us to do this, please get in touch on [info@raindance.co.uk](mailto:info@raindance.co.uk).  
You have the legal right to request a copy of the data that we hold about you. If you would like a copy of some or all of the information we hold about you, please email [info@raindance.co.uk](mailto:info@raindance.co.uk).

#### Opting out of marketing

We may communicate with you about ourselves, our events, ways to support us and other Raindance loveliness. We will usually only do this if you tell us we can, for example by joining our mailing list. If you aren’t on our mailing list, but you have previously attended or enquired about a Raindance event or class, we may occasionally get in touch about similar projects we think you’ll want to know about.

You have the right to tell us to stop contacting you for marketing purposes. If you want to opt out, just email [info@raindance.co.uk](mailto:info@raindance.co.uk) to let us know, or click ‘unsubscribe’ within the email we have sent you via MailChimp
